Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 14 -- Materials held at the University of Pennsylvania 1705-1788 Mss.B.F85inventory14
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence (University of Pennsylvania), 1758-1788
  - Miscellaneous Letters, [1777.]; 1p.; Memorandum
    A.N. by Dr. Franklin. Applications to go to America; sale of vessels in Holland; prizes; complaints of Spain and Holland; financial matters.
  - to Jonathan Williams, Jr., [1777.]; 1p.; Mercier, -----
    Intemized account of expenditures on behalf of the United States.
  - to ----- Mercier., [1777.]; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Accusing him of leaving his work unfinished and breaking his contract; referring him to Dr. Franklin for a settlement of his account.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, [1777.]; 1p.; The Supreme Executive Council of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. Philadelphia
    A stirring call to arms to defend the City and Philadelphia from the imminent attack of the British army. S. Thomas Wharton, Jr., President.
  - to His Uncle., L. 2p.; Boux, -----
    Complaining of the insulting treatment offered him on board the "Lion"; given a passage on this ship by Jonathan Williams, Jr.; rails against the manners of American seamen.
    (Copy translated into English.)
  - Appendix, 1777; A. Mem. 3p.; Alexander, William
    Observations on tobacco.
  - to ----- Mercier., 1778 February 5; 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Concerning his debt to Mercier.
  - to Sam[ue]l Tucker., 1773 February 10; 2p.; The Navy Board, Eastern Department. Boston
    Instructions concerning Capt. Tucker's passenger, John Adams. S. W[illia]m Vernon and James Warren.
  - to J[ames] Moylan., 1778 February 17; L.S. 1p.; Lee, Arthur. Chaillot
    Advising him not to settle in l'Orient in order to transact public business for the American Commissioners because it had been reported that his purpose was to promote the private interests of said Commissioners.
  - to Arthur Lee., 1778 February 23; L. 2p.; Moylan, James. L'Orient
    Stigmatizes as false the report mentioned in his letter of the 17th inst.; thinks the source of his information should be divulged.
  - Appendix, 1778 March 3; A. Mem. 1p.; Franklin, William Temple
    A list of letters and papers sent to Arthur Lee.
  - to ----- Moreau., 1778 March 13; Mem. 1p.; Perrin, -----
    Receipt for duties paid on wine.
  - to Abraham Whipple., 1778 March; L.S. William Vernon. 2p.; The Navy Board, Eastern Department
    Instructions to Capt. Whipple relative to his voyage to France.
    Copy attested by Geo[rge] Richards, Sec[retar]y.
  - to Abraham Whipple, Commander of the Ship "Providence.", 1778 April 25; L.S. William Vernon. 2p.; The Navy Board, Eastern Department. Providence
    Instructions concerning the treatment of prizes and prisoners.
  - to Thomas Simpson., 1778 April 26; L.S. 1p.; Jones, Capt. John Paul. "Ranger."
    Appointing him Commander of the prize-ship of war "Drake" and giving him his instructions.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1778 April 30; L.S. 1p.; Chantereyne, ----- de. Cherbourg
    Acknowledging his debt to William Addiscott.
  - to The People of the United States., 1778 May 9; 1p.; The Continental Congress
    Recounting the cruelty with which Great Britain has waged the war; adjuring them not to accept their offers of peace and urging them to be firm. Printed proclamation. Yorktown, Printed by Hall and Sellers.
  - to [Barbeu] Dubourg, Paris., 1778 May 16; A.L.S. 2p.; du Buisson, Chevalier. La Flèche
    Desiring a letter of recommendation for his nephew who goes to join the army in America; begs him to obtain permission from Dr. Franklin for his nephew to go on board the "Boston."
  - ----- Loyal, Paris., 1778 May 19; A.L.S. 1p.; Melmoth, Courtney. Flanders
    Obliged to go to England; promises to pay him what he owes.
  - to Chevalier de Beauteville., [1778. May ?]; L. 1p.; -----, -----
    Asking for letters of recommendation from Dr. Franklin and others for M. d'Abezac.
  - to ----- -----., 1778 May 24; A.L.S. 1p.; de Beauteville, Chevalier. Paris
    Accepts his offer of letters of recommendation from Dr. Franklin for the Chevalier d'Abezac.
  - to Capt. Corbin Barnes., 1778 June 8; L.S. J[ames] Warren, J[ohn] Deshon. 1p.; The Navy Board, Eastern Department. Boston
    Ordering him to prepare the "Despatch" for sea, and then report to the Council.
  - to Capt. Corbin Barnes., 1778 June 9; L.S. Jer[emiah] Powell, Presid[en]t. 2p.; The State of Massachusetts Bay. Council Chamber, Watertown
    Entrusting him with letters for the American Commissioners at Paris. Minute orders as to his future procedure; secrecy enjoined.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 11; D.S. 1p.; Fallon, Andrew. On board the "Drake," Brest
    His parole as a British prisoner of war.
  - to Peltier Du Doyer., 1778 June 15; D.S. 1p.; Leconte, -----. Nantes
    Official notice to produce certificates of discharge for certain vessels within a given time.
    (In French. Partly printed.)
  - Appendix, 1777 March 1; 1778 May 9, June 19; D.S. 3p.; The Continental Congress
    Resolutions pertaining to the appointment of Capt. [Pierre] Landais, to command certain vessels.
  - to ----- ------., 1778 June 26; L.S. 2p.; Montieu, Jean-Josef Carié de. Paris
    Unjust and illegal duties levied by the Farmers-General on goods sent by him to America; desires to obtain Dr. Franklin's influence with the Comte de Maurepas to have these abolished; enclosing a memoir on the subject [3p.].
  - to [Ferdinand] Grand, Paris., 1778 July 1; A.L.S. 1p.; Boudet, -----. Paris
    Sending one of the five installments of notes promised to Dr. Franklin.
  - to [Whom it May Concern]., 1778 July 10; L.S. 1p.; Brisbois, -----. Dunkirk
    Certificate by the Mayor and Alderman of Dunkirk as to [François] Jean Coffyn's honesty and trustworthiness.
  - Dr. [James] Lloyd., 1778 August 10; L.S. 3p.; Hutchinson, Thomas. London
    Sending him a power of attorney to collect the rent on his sister's estate on Slocum's Island; confers power of attorney for his own estates at Milton and Dorchester.
    (Copy attested by Jona[than] Loring Austin.)
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1778 August 14; L. in 3d P. 3p.; Smith, Dr. James. Paris
    Reminding him of his Grandfather's promise to secure passage through France for the writer and his baggage; the latter detained at Calais for three months; demands that his goods be released at once.
  - to Dr. [James] Smith., 1778 August 16; A.L.S. 2p.; Franklin, William Temple. Passy
    Takes exception to the tone of his letter; points out the formalities needed before his baggage can be released.
  - to ----- -----., 1778 September 4; L. 2p.; ------, -----. Newburyport
    Account of an incursion into Rhode Island by the American troops, supported by the French fleet.
  - to ----- -----., 1778 October 1; L. 1p.; -----, -----. Nantes
    Announcing the retreat of the Royalisrs from Rhode Island to Long Island; Comte d'Estaing's position off Sandy Hook.
  - to ----- de Montieu., 1778 December 23; A.L.S. 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Acknowledging the receipt of a quantity of clothing and military stores.
  - to Louis XVI., 1778; Diss. 25p.; Necker, Jacques. Paris
    Suggesting a plan for improving the French Provincial Administration.
  - to [William] Carmichael., L. in 3d P. 1p.; -----, -----. Paris
    Proposal to meet him at an appointed time near the statue in the Rue Vendome; a signal is described and secrecy is enjoined.
  - Appendix, 1779 February 2 and 3; Mem. 8p.; Landais, Capt. Pierre. On board the "Alliance."
    Proceedings of a Board of Inquiry, held to investigate a conspiracy to take the "Alliance" by force and carry her into England or Ireland.
  - to John Paul Jones., 1779 February 19; A.L. in 3d P. 2p.; Schweighauser, John D. Nantes
    Pursuant to Dr. Franklin's orders, he will deliver the [Countess of Selkirk's] plate deposited in the King's warehouse; asks him to bring a silversmith that the plate may be valued according to law.
  - to John Paul Jones., 1779 March 3; A.L.S. 1p.; d'Orvilliers, Louis Guillouet Comte. Brest
    Offers his services and those of the Commandant at Brest. Question of the transference of Lieut. [Thomas] Simpson from the prison ship to a prison on land.
  - to [Richard Bennett Lloyd]., 1779 March 5; L.S. 2p.; Lloyd, Edward. Annapolis
    Proposed shipment of tobacco delayed by the presence of the enemy's privateers. Question of sending him bills of exchange. Peace expected soon.
  - to ----- -----., 1779 March 6; L. 2p.; -----, -----. St. Eustache
    Account of the arrival of various ships escorted by French frigates; positions of Comte d'Estaing and Comte de Grasse.
  - to His Nephew., 1779 March 30; L.S. 2p.; Lloyd, Richard. Farley
    Upon the advice of Gen. [John] Cadwalader, J. H. Hallyday and James Tilghman, he agrees to let his nephew draw upon him for funds.
  - to John Bondfield., 1779 August 5; Mem. S. 1p.; Louis Sazerac l'ainé and fils. Bordeaux
    Bill for cannon bought for the United States.
    E. by John Bondfield. By order of Capt. [John] P[aul] Jones the above cannon were forwarded to l'Orient.
  - to The Court-Martial, on board the "Bon Homme Richard.", 1779 August 8; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Jones, Capt. John Paul
    The decision of the Court-Martial for the trial of Lieutenant [Robert] Robinson returned for consideration; recommends that disqualification be added to the sentence.
  - to ----- -----., 1779 August 11; L. 1p.; -----, -----. Rotterdam
    News of the defeat of the British army near Charlestown; losses of the Americans and English; Pulaski's Cavalry made 180 prisoners.
  - John Ross, Paris., 1779 August 11; A.L.S. 1p.; Craig, J. Rotterdam
    News of the American victory at Charlestown; congratulations; British surrender to [Gen. Benjamin] Lincoln and [Gen. William] Moultrie; Gen. [Sir Henry] Clinton did nothing at Stony Point.
  - to John Paul Jones., 1779 August 12; L.S. 1p.; ----- Taillot and other Officers of the "Vengeance". Groa
    Desertion so rife that the remaining crew are unable to execute military manoeuvres; nineteen raw recruits; beg that this state of things may be remedied.
    (In French. Copy attested by Jno. P[aul] Jones.)
  - Appendix, 1779 July to August; A. Mem. S. D[enis] N[icolas] Cottineau de Kloguene, President, et al. 15p.; Minutes of a Court-Martial held for the Trail of Lieut. Robert Robinson. On board the "Bon Homme Richard, " L'Orient
    Sentenced to discharge from the service and disqualification for future official position in the navy of the United States.
  - to The Framers-General., 1779 August; Diss. 22p.; The Chamber of Commerce of Dunkirk
    Objections to the proposed duty on tobacco form prize cargoes entering Dunkirk from French ports.
  - to Capt. Pierre Landais., 1779 September 2 and 5; L.S. 1p. each.; Jones, Capt. John Paul. "Bon Homme Richard"
    Desiring his immediate presence on board the "Bon Homme Richard."
  - to John Paul Jones., 1779 September 2 and 5; L.S. 1p. each.; Landais, Capt. Pierre. On board the "Alliance."
    Declining to obey Captain Jones's orders.
  - to John Langley and William Denham., 1779 September 21; D. 1 sheet.; George III. London
    Letter of Marque, permitting them to fit out the vessel "Chambers" as a man-of-war and to go forth as a privateer.
    (On parchment. Framed.)
  - to Capt. Pierre Landais., 1779 September 23; L.S. M[athew] Parke, C[aptain of] M[arines], et al. 3p.; The Officers of the "Alliance"
    Defending the action of the "Alliance" during the fight with the "Serapis."
    (A. Copy attested by William Temple Franklin.)
  - to Marquis [Alexandre] d'Hanache, Paris., 1779 September 23; A.L.S. 2p.; William Alexander, Lord Stirling. On the Heights of Spitsberg
    His position as commander in the United States army; [Marquis de] la Fayette served under him, and was wounded at the battle of Brandywine; glad of the American-French Alliance.
  - to John Paul Jones., 1779 October 10; A.L.S. 4p.; Wuybert, Antoine-Félix. On board the "Serapis."
    Desiring to return to America in his former capacity as engineer.
    A.E. by John Paul Jones, begging Dr. Franklin to grant the above request.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1779 October 22; A.L.S. 4p.; Wuybert, Antoine-Félix. On board the "Serapis."
    Formal charges against Capt. Pierre Landais, of insubordination to his superior, Commodore John Paul Jones.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1779 October 30; D.S. M[athew] Parke, C[aptain of] M[arines], et al. 16p.; Landais, Capt. Pierre. Texel
    Defense in the proceedings of a court-martial for his trial.
  - Appendix, 1780 September 23; Mem. S. 1p.; Jones, Capt. John Paul
    List of officers and men belonging to the "Ariel," under his command.
  - to ----- -----., [1780. September ?]; Mem. 2p.; -----, -----
    List of officers and men belonging to the "Ariel" under Capt. [John Paul] Jones's command.
  - to ----- -----., [1780. September ?]; Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    List of volunteers belonging to the ship "Ariel."
  - Appendix, 1780 December 5; A. Bill S. 1p.; Bondfield, John. Bordeaux
    Bill for cannon bought from Louis Sazerac Painé and fils, shipped on the "Marquis de la Fayette."
  - Appendix, 1780; A.N. 1p.; Chaumont, Le Ray de
    When one of two nations at war loses its credit, the domination of the other is assured; if America loses her credit she must accept peace.
  - Appendix, 1780; Mem. 2p.; Chaumont, Le Ray de
    Project for sinking the paper money.
  - Appendix, 1780; Mem. 1p.; Landais, Capt. Pierre
    Denies having received instruction from M. [Le Ray] de Chaumont to put himself under the command of Capt. [John Paul] Jones, or to fulfil Benjamin Franklin's orders of July 28, 1779.
  - Appendix, [1780.]; Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    List of petty officers on board the "Alliance."
  - Appendix, [1780.]; Mem. 10p.; -----, -----
    List of officers and men on board the "Alliance" under the command of Peter Landais.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, [1780.]; Mem. 2p.; -----, -----
    List of dates under the headings "to M. [Pierre] Landais," and" to officers of the 'Alliance,'" and "to M. [Alexander] Gillon."
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    List of fourteen despatches, sent by the "Mercury" packet, Capt. [Simon] Samson.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1781 January 13; D.S. 1p.; Deane, Silas. Paris
    Certifying that he has not sold any of the certificates which Mr. [John] Shee gave him power of attorney to sell, and that he has deposited the power of attorney with Dr. Franklin.
  - to The Marquis de Castries., 1781 February 13; L.S. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    The "Marquis de la Fayette" preparing to carry munitions of war and supplies to America; asks for orders to the officers at l'Orient to assist these preparations; asks for a convoy to Rhode Island.
  - to The Continental Congress., 1781 April 20; Mem. 6p.; Deane, Silas. Paris
    Itemized account against Congress.
  - to [Ferdinand] Grand., L. 2p.; Horneca, Fizeaux and Co. Amsterdam
    Concerning the Dutch loan.
  - to The Public., 1781 May 28; 1p.; Morris, Robert. Philadelphia
    Plan for the establishment of a National Bank for the United States of North America. Printed broadside.
  - to Morel fils., 1781 June 1; D.S. 1p.; Gillon, Alexander. Dunkirk
    An order to pay sixty livres a month to Madame Virth, whose husband is a volunteer in the service of South Carolina.
  - Appendix, 1781 June 29; Engraved L.S. 2p.; Baulny?, -----. Newtown
    Order of the Treasurer of War to pay a certain sum of Messrs. Wadswoth and Carter for supplies furnished to the army of Comte de Rochambeau.
    E. by Wadsworth and Carter and by Jon[a]th[an] Trumbull.
  - to ----- -----., 1781 August 16; L.S. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Proposal to furnish arms for the use of the United States.
  - Appendix, 1781 September 12; D.S. George Bond, Deputy Secretary. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Resolved that Mr. [Silas] Deane's accounts be examined by a Vice-Consul and that Mr. Deane be informed of the appointment of said Vice-Consul.
  - to [Francis] Coffyn., [1781. October.]; A.L.S. 2p.; Beer, Thomas. Dunkirk
    Needs a letter of recommendation in order to transport himself and family to America. Could not get work in town because rope-making was slack and he was regarded as a spy.
  - to Silas Deane., 1781 November; L.S. 4p.; Wadsworth, Jeremiah. Williamsburg
    [Silas] Deane mistaken in his gloomy picture of American affairs; explains what he believes to be Spain's attitude.
  - to Silas Deane., 1781 December 27; L.S. 7p.; Tallmadge, Major Benjamin. Withersfield
    Concerning the interception and publication of a letter said to be addressed to him by Mr. [Silas] Deane, in which union with Great Britain is advocated; Shows how groundless are the arguments used; believes in ultimate independence.
    Printed in Collections of New York Historical Society, 1889. Deane Papers, IV, 557.
  - to George Fox., 1781 December 28; D.S. 1p.; Adams, John. Amsterdam
    Passport for Mr. Fox to be used in France.
    Signed also by J[ohn] Thaxter, Sec[retar]y.
  - to ----- Brentano., 1782 January 29; Wadsworth, Col. Jeremiah. Williamsburg
    Pained at parting with him. Sends him two letters to Mr. [Silas] Deane, one from Major [Benjamin] Tallmadge, the other from himself.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1782; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Brentano, -----. Paris
    Desires to know what he shall do with the letters delivered to him by Col. [Jeremiah] Wadsworth, just returned from Germany, and is to go back to the army in Virginia.
  - to Messrs. [Jean] de Neufville and Sons, Amsterdam., 1782 March 9; L.S. 1p.; Morris, Robert. Office of Finance Philadelphia
    Advising them to follow Dr. Franklin's orders as regards the goods belonging to the United States, in their possession.
  - to [Gen.] George Washington., 1782 May 7; L.S. 2p.; Carleton, Sir Guy. New York
    Announcing his appointment as Commander of the British forces on the Atlantic; deputed to act with Admiral [Robert] Digby on the Peace Commission; transmits papers to show that the British desire peace.
  - to Sir Guy Carleton., 1782 May 10; L.S. 1p.; Washington, Gen. George. Headquarters
    Concerning his requests for a passport for Mr. Morgan. British flags of truce will be received only at Dobbs's Ferry, so long as the armies occupy their present position.
  - to Louis XVI., 1782 May 20; L. 3p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Congratulatory letter upon the birth of the Dauphin.
  - to Miss Bethia Alexander., [1782. June.]; A.L.S. 2p.; Eonnefoux, -----. Paris
    She kindly undertook to induce Dr. Franklin to accept the dedication which was presented to him by one of their Professors of Philosophy, and he realizes that this act of condescension of this illustrious man is due to her. Begs her to communicate to Dr. Franklin that it will necessary for him to write to the Academy of Sciences of Toulouse, requesting it to represent him in this public act, and enclosing a form for such a request.
  - Appendix, 1782 July 23; Printed D.S. Tho[ma]s Allan, et al. 1p.; Thomas Allan and Others. London
    Certificate for the vessel, the "Lyon of Bristol," that gives bond to return to Great Britain only.
  - to [Gen.] George Washington, 1782 August 12; L.S. 2p.; Sir Guy Carleton and Admiral Robert Digby. New York
    Lord Grenville has gone to Paris with full powers to treat for peace; offer of independence to America; probable concessions to the American loyalists. Mr. [Henry] Laurens's release; question of the exchange of prisoners.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1782 [1783?] August 12; A.L.S. 2p.; Mumford, G.S. Nantes
    Introducing M. Le Grand Cannon and his companion, Mr. Russell. Concerning a letter from Dr. Franklin to Dr. [David] Hartley, containing a dialogue between some wreckers and a captain of a ship.
  - to Lair De Lamotte. Passy., 1782 September 11; A.L.S. 2p.; Lamarque, -----. Paris
    Account of the use he has made of the money advanced to him by M. [Alexander] Gillon; begs him to call Dr. Franklin's attention to the matter.
  - to Madame [Brillon?], 1782 September 25.; A.L.S. 1p.; Vernet, -----. Paris
    Asking her influence with Dr. Franklin to procure a passage to America for M. [Laurent] Josselin, a civil and military engineer.
  - to Ferdinand Grand., 1782 October 8; A.L.S. 1p.; Wyld, Henry. Londonderry
    Desiring the secure a passage to Philadelphia, on a French vessel.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1781 October 5 to 1782 October 12; 3p.; The Continental Congress
    Thomas Barclay's commission as Consul to France; the King's Exequatur. Copies.
    (In English and French.)
  - to Marquis de la Fayette., [1782.]; A.L. in 3d P. 3p.; Charles Grant, Vicomte de Vaux
    His fortune lost in aiding the American cause; desires as a sort of indemnity, a tract of land on some navigable river in America.
  - to Governor William Franklin., A.L. in 3d P. 2p.; Newenham, Sir Edward
    Glad to learn of the Governor's safe arrival in England; offers to carry to Dr. Franklin, in Paris, any message not political.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, [1782.]; A.D. 1p.; Thun, Ulrich, baron de. Paris
    Copy of a receipt signed by Richard Bache, Administrator of the estate of Frederick Hoeckl[er]in, for £200 received from Christian. Schneider.
    (In French and German.)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, [1782.]; Printed Mem. 2p.; Explanation of a Medal Struck by the Americans in 1782, in Honor of the Capitulations of Saratoga and York Town
    Shows France guarding the infant Republic from Great Britain.
    (In French and English, in parallel columns.)
  - Misellaneous Letters, 1783 February 17; 17p.; William Petty, Earl of Shelburne. London
    Speech in the House of Lords, on the King's address on behalf of peace. [See Hansard's Parliamentary Debates, XXIII, 407-420.]
  - to ----- Hoffman., 1783 April 10; L.S. 1p.; William Temple Franklin, Gustavus H. Temple and Samuel Vaughan le jeune. Paris
    Thanking him for his courtesy in permitting them to see his important invention of the "polytype."
  - to William Temple Franklin, Passy., 1783 April 13; A.L.S. 2p.; White, Samuel. London
    Mr. [Charles James] Fox's proposal to admit American vessels on the basis of 1763, until a Commerical Treaty can be concluded. Desires to know if his grandfather can give American papers for a ship bought in England by an American. Family affairs.
  - to William Temple Franklin, Passy., 1783 June 18; A.L.S. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Desiring Dr. Franklin's assistance in securing a Captain's license for M. de la Ville.
  - Appendix, 1783 July 3; Mem. 3p.; "M. Lavoisies, Desmaret, L'Abbé Bossut et Mof." Annonay
    Description of an ascension made in the aerostatic machine invented by the brothers [Joseph Michel and Jacques Etienne] Montgolfier.
  - to William Temple Franklin, Passy., 1783 August 8; A.L.S. 2p.; Vaughan, Benjamin. London
    Concerning a note received from Jonathan Williams. [Sr.?], which did not prove good.
  - to William Temple Franklin, Passy., 1783 September 16; A.L.S. 1p.; Caffiéri, Jean Jacques
    Dr. Franklin's bust packed ready for shipment; only the name of its destination needed.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1783 November 21; Mem. 3p.; Duc de Polignac, Duc de Guines, Comte de Polastron, Comte Vaudreuil, ----- d'Hunaud, Benjamin Franklin, Faujas de Saint Fond, ----- Delisle, [Jean Baptiste] Le Roy. Chateau de la Muette
    Enthusiastic description of an ascension made in M. Montgolfier's aerostatic machine; it carried two passengers, the Marquis d'Orlandes and M. Pilâtre de Rozier.
  - to The Continental Congress., A.L. 1p.; Deane, Silas, 1737-1789
    His bill against Congress; three charges cited a having been wrongfully made; reimbursement sought.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1783; 1p.; "An Ode in Imitation of Alcæus."
    Printed by B[enjamin] F[ranklin] Bache. Passy, 1783. Printed broadside.
  - to William Temple Franklin, Passy., L.S. 1p.; Pechigny, Madame Devillier